翻译　Wanderlust　多星人　My other　atlas
字　　幕　　侠
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
翻译　奶瓶且可爱99　文生云　宇宙的大柚子
ZIMUXIA.CN
校对　宇宙的大柚子　多星人　时间轴　iiichiii
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
监制　宇宙的大柚子
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
ZIMUXIA.CN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
我是 沙琳
I'm, um, Charlene.
普雷·泰尔的妈妈
Pray Tell's mother.
我能进去跟你聊聊吗
Can I come in and talk to you for a minute?
母亲之间的谈话
Mother to mother.
我泡了些冰茶
I got some ice tea brewed.
那是他的...
Um, is-is that his...
对
Yes.
看来哈特岛上没有他的位置了
I guess no pine box on Hart Island for him?
[纽约东北部埋尸岛]
我 很惭愧
I'm, um, ashamed.
我知道你对我儿子来说有多重要
I know what you were to my son.
你是他最好的朋友
His best friend.
他的姐妹
His sister.
他真正的妈妈
His real mother.
普雷要是能看到我俩一起坐在这 会说什么呢
What would Pray say now if he could see the two of us sitting here?
我想这可能是唯一能让他
I think that might have been the only thing
说不出话的事情吧
that might have ever made him speechless.
我觉得你现在最好不去想
You know, I think it's best you put any regret
你跟普雷之间的遗憾
about you and Pray away, right now.
否则你余生每次想起他
Or else that's all you gonna think about of him
-都只剩遗憾  -我知道 我知道
- for the rest of your life. - I know. I know.
但我愿付出一切来换取再跟他多待一分钟
But what I wouldn't give to get one more minute with him.
这样想...
Well...
这一切都自有定数
We got all the minutes we gonna get.
我...
I...
我来这是想请你帮个忙
I came here to ask you a favor.
普雷写了遗嘱
Pray wrote a will,
把遗嘱执行权给了我妹妹 杰达
and he gave his power of attorney to my sister, Jada.
我几乎是跪下求她
I had to practically get on my knees and beg her
让我完成其中一个遗愿
to let me fulfill one of his last wishes.
把他带到这个世界的是我啊
I brought him into this world.
而且...
And...
算了 谢天谢地 她最终同意了
Well, anyway. Thank the Lord that she finally agreed.
但没有你的帮助我无法完成那个遗愿
But I can't fulfill that wish without your help.
要我做什么你尽管说
Anything. Just tell me what to do.
这是普雷一半的骨灰
This is half of Pray's ashes.
我保留了另一半
I kept the other half for myself.
你觉得他能接受吗
You think he'd be okay with that?
我觉得他会希望如此
I think he would want that.
他留下了这些心形吊坠盒
He left these heart-shaped lockets.
他想让你在每个小盒子里放一点他的骨灰
He wants you to put a little of him in each one,
然后把它们送给对他最重要的人
and give it to those who are most precious to him.
至于剩下的 你想怎么处理都行
Whatever you have left, you can do what you want.
洒了还是留着都行
Scatter them. Keep them.
你也有作为母亲的权利 布兰卡
You've got mother's rights too, Blanca.
放心交给我吧
I'll take care of everything.
他...
He...
他亲手为你做的
He made this one for you.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
我能...
May I...
帮你戴上吗
put it on you?
谢谢你爱我的孩子
Thank you for loving my baby.
好了...
Well...
-我该走了  -好
- I better get out of here. - Okay.
占用你够长时间的了
Took up enough of your time.
沙琳 等等
Ch-Charlene, wait.
我再也没机会与普雷相处了
I can't have any more minutes with Pray,
但我很高兴能还有机会
but I'm so glad that I got to share
与你共度这几分钟
these few minutes with you.
FIX字　侠 译制
FIX字幕侠 译制
主题是...
The category is...
活出彩...
Live...
浪起来...
Work...
秀出姿态
Pose!
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
●
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
姿态
第三季 第８集
"大结局·下"
蛋白酶抑制剂简直是奇迹
These protease inhibitors are a miracle.
我眼看着我的病人完全康复了
I'm watching my patients make full recoveries
如果没有这个药的话
from something that would've otherwise
他们就要去见阎王了
sent them to they graves.
我们称之为"拉撒路效应"
We're calling it "The Lazarus Effect."
[圣经中耶稣让死去的拉撒路复活]
现在问题不再是"做什么"
The question is no longer, "What do we do?"
而是"怎么做"
but, "How do we do it?"
没错 没错 说得好
Right. Right. Exactly.
一些人有幸参与了临床试验
Some of us are lucky enough to get into the trials,
但还有那些负担不起
but what about those who can't afford
每年一万的药费的人呢
$10,000 a year for new meds?
这个操蛋的问题已经困扰我们很久了
It's the same fucking problem we've always had.
政客与大制药公司拖拖拉拉不肯行动
Politicians and Big Pharma are dragging their asses,
因为我们的生命对他们来说一文不值
because our lives mean nothing to them.
所以我们要把这次抗议游行向前推进一步
That's why we've got to take this next protest a step further.
我有个主意 我有个主意
Here's an idea. Here's an idea.
很激进 但要引起那些混蛋的重视
It's a radical step, but it's a necessary one to get
这是必要的一步
these motherfuckers' attention,
因为我们永远也得不到他们的共情
because we will never have their empathy
-或同情  -没错
- or compassion. - No.
所以 我们要把逝去的亲朋的骨灰
So, we are gonna release the ashes of those we've lost
洒到市长门前的草坪上
onto the mayor's fucking front lawn.
那样一来 他就不会再将死亡看作区区数字
That way, he won't just see the dead as just a number anymore.
这里有谁愿意做出这个牺牲
Who here is willing to make this kind of sacrifice?!
两天前我儿子去世时
When my son died two days ago,
他叫我把他的骨灰洒在药监局门口
he asked me to drop his body on the doorsteps of the FDA,
但我觉得你的提议更有力
but I think this can be even more powerful.
算我一个
Count me in.
-也算我一个  -我们上
- Me, too. - Yeah, let's do it!
操他娘的 反正我们也被逼到尽头了
Fuck yeah. We got nothing to lose.
好 我们投个票
Okay, let's take a vote.
有谁觉得 他们的至亲至爱
Who here thinks that their loved ones
会希望自己的骨灰成为这段历史的见证
would want their ashes to be a part of this history?
同志们 我们失去了
Guys, we have lost thousands
成千上万的人
and thousands of people,
-而他们只能静静待在...  -没错
- and they are just sitting... - Yes!
骨灰盒里 无法战斗
In urns, inactive.
要我说
Well, if you ask me,
他们就是为崇高事业而死的革命者
they were revolutionaries who died for a cause.
-没错  -他们从坟墓里呼唤着
- Yeah! - They are calling out,
要为此献一份力
beyond the grave, to be in service.
-好  -他们想在最后的斗争中贡献力量
- Yes! - And they want to be active in our final fight.
谁愿意
Who is willing
再向这个世界传递一个信息
to send one more message out into the world?
来争取那些救命药
To demand access to these lifesaving meds
阻止无尽的死亡
to stop the endless death?
我愿意 我愿意
I will. I will!
行动 行动 行动
ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP!
ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP!
行动 行动 行动
ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP!
行动 行动
ACT UP! ACT UP!
行动 行动 行动
ACT UP! ACT UP! ACT UP!
你还好吗
You okay?
还好 宝贝
Yeah, baby.
大家都到了
Everyone's here.
你们可能都纳闷为什么来这里
Y'all are probably wondering why y'all here.
这里是普雷的庇护所
This was Pray's sanctuary.
他的家
His home.
我们在这里度过了很多快乐时光
We had some good times here.
我想 没有比这里更适合
And I couldn't think of a more fitting place
完成他遗愿的地方了
to carry out his final wish.
你们都是他最珍视的人
Y'all were most precious to him.
你们都给予了他很多
And y'all gave him so much.
他希望让你们所有人
And he wanted to make sure that each of you
都能拥有他的一部分
have a little bit of him.
谢谢
Thanks.
Thank you.
谢谢
普雷本来说不打算给你的
Originally, Pray's instructions was not to give you one of these.
但他只是开玩笑
But he was just playing around.
"伊莱察...
"Elektra...
伊莱察每天都在为自己争取
Elektra fights every day to get what's hers,
看起来或许有些自私
and maybe that looks like a selfish act,
但事实是
but the truth is,
每当伊莱察有所得
every time Elektra gets herself something,
都在向我们展示世界的广阔
she shows all of us, the world,
我们的潜力巨大
how much we are capable of.
我们值得更好的"
How much we deserve."
他其实给每个人都写了几句话
He actually wrote down a little something about all of you.
我想这是在他意识到
I guess it was back when he was sure
自己时日无多时写下的
that he didn't have too long left.
露露
Lulu.
他说你内心有真正强大的力量
He said you got a real strength in you, girl.
有时候
And that sometimes,
当他觉得自己已经无力抗争了
when he was feeling like he couldn't fight no more,
他会想起你那副从来不在乎别人怎么说的态度
he would think of you, and how you never took any shit off no one.
那会让他开怀大笑
And that made him laugh,
帮他度过难熬的夜晚
and it would get him through the night.
朱迪...
And, Judy...
他说你让他终于相信
He said you actually made him believe
白人里也有好人
in the goodness of white people.
安吉尔和帕比...
And, Angel and Papi...
他从未想到在自己身边 在我们的社区中
He never thought that so close to home, in our neighborhood,
我们的群体中
in our community,
他能见到电影中才有的
he would ever see the kind of romance and love
浪漫爱情
that he saw in the movies.
真实 真正的爱
Real, true love.
在最黑暗的时光里
And in these darkest times,
你们的爱让他对未来又有了希望
your love gave him hope for the future.
还有尊敬的评审团...
And to the Great Council...
曼哈顿 卡索 杰克
Manhattan, Castle and Jack.
他说...
He said...
"朋友们 我们撑起了这个疯狂的世界
"Fellas, we held our crazy world together,
我们是领头人 是舞会的四根台柱子
the tribal chiefs, the four pillars of the ballroom.
我留给世界的一切 都归功于你们给予的友谊
Whatever legacy I leave behind, I owe it to your friendship
以及你们对舞会的无私奉献"
and your commitment to the magic of the balls."
瑞奇
And, Ricky.
他向你写道
To you he wrote,
"和你在一起 我感觉从未老去 也未有伤病
"I was never old. I was never sick with you.
我不必成为舞台上的主持人或者一位家父
I didn't have to be an emcee on a stage or a father.
在我们共度的美好时光中 我不需要表演
In the best moments we shared, there was no performance.
我只是我"
I was just me."
普雷跟你说了什么 妈
What did Pray say to you, Ma?
什么都没说
Nothing.
我们之间没有什么未尽之言
There was nothing ever left unsaid between us.
我们还有一件事要做
There's one more thing we got to do.
普雷从未提及此事
Something that Pray never asked,
但我知道他一定希望如此
but I know he would want.
我没有把骨灰都放进项链里
I didn't use all those ashes up in those lockets.
我们要把剩下的骨灰 放在一个特别的地方
We gonna use the rest of them, and put them somewhere special.
行动 反抗 抗艾
ACT UP! Fight back! Fight AIDS!
♪ 某天他会前来 ♪
♪ Someday he'll come along ♪
♪ 我的所爱之人 ♪
♪ The man I love ♪
♪ 他会高大强壮 ♪
♪ And he'll be big and strong ♪
♪ 我的所爱之人 ♪
♪ The man I love ♪
♪ 当他来我到身边 ♪
♪ And when he comes my way ♪
♪ 我会尽我所能 ♪
♪ I'll do my best ♪
♪ 让他驻足停留 ♪
♪ To make him stay ♪
♪ 他会与我相视而笑 ♪
♪ He'll look at me and smile ♪
♪ 我就会明白 ♪
♪ I'll understand ♪
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
体制杀人
安息 死于
安慰剂的孩子们
♪ 不多时 ♪
♪ And in a little while ♪
♪ 他就会握住我的手 ♪
♪ He'll take my hand ♪
♪ 尽管这或许有些荒唐 ♪
♪ And though it seems absurd ♪
♪ 但我知道我们 ♪
♪ I know we both ♪
♪ 都会不发一言 ♪
♪ Won't say a word ♪
♪ 或许我会在周日与他相遇 ♪
♪ Maybe I shall meet him Sunday ♪
♪ 也可能是周一 ♪
♪ Maybe Monday ♪
♪ 也可能不是 ♪
♪ Maybe not ♪
活出彩 浪起来 秀出姿态 -普雷·泰尔
♪ 但我确定 某日我终会与他相遇 ♪
♪ Still I'm sure to meet him one day ♪
活出彩 浪起来 秀出姿态 -普雷·泰尔
♪ 可能是在周二 ♪
♪ Maybe Tuesday ♪
♪ 可能是我福音沓来的那天 ♪
♪ Will be my good news day ♪
♪ 他会构筑一个小家 ♪
♪ He'll build a little home ♪
♪ 只为我们二人而造 ♪
♪ Just meant for two ♪
♪ 我不会再漂泊不定 ♪
♪ From which I'll never roam ♪
♪ 谁会呢 你会吗 ♪
♪ Who would? Would you? ♪
♪ 所以最重要的是 ♪
♪ And so, all else above ♪
♪ 我在等待 ♪
♪ I'm waiting for ♪
♪ 我的所爱之人 ♪
♪ The man I love ♪
♪ 所以最重要的是 ♪
♪ And so All else above ♪
♪ 我在等待 ♪
♪ I'm waiting for ♪
♪ 我的所爱之人 ♪
♪ The man I Love. ♪
只有生日蛋糕才要蜡烛 你怎么蠢兮兮的
Candles are for birthday cakes. Why you got to be so silly?
这比生日更重要
This is more important than a birthday.
因为从今天起 我的宝贝正式成为了一名护士
Because as of today, my baby girl's officially a nurse.
除此之外 今天还是我们四周年纪念日
And on top of all of that, it's our four-year anniversary.
现在 吹蜡烛吧
Now, go on and blow out that candle
省得蜡油滴得到处都是
before it drips all over the place.
快吹 宝贝 搞这么复杂
Go on, girl. You're so dramatic.
我得许个愿
I got to make a wish.
所以 这是胡萝卜蛋糕和奶油干酪
So, it's carrot cake and cream cheese?
都是你的最爱
Your favorite.
谢谢你理解这周六对我的意义
Thanks for understanding about Saturday.
当然 你有你的安排
Of course. You got to do what you got to do.
做你自己的事
Do your thing.
下周末再庆祝我们的纪念日
We'll celebrate our anniversary next weekend.
-好吧  -但同时呢
- Okay. - But, in the meantime,
我也想想你能做些什么
I'll just be thinking of all the things you could do
-来弥补一下我  -你恶心惹
- to make it up to me. - You so nasty.
-你喜欢吗  -喜欢
- You love it? - I do.
你最近有见过朱迪吗
You been up there to see Judy yet?
她还在四楼工作吗
Is she still working up on the fourth floor?
还在那层
Same floor.
但工作不一样了
It's a different gig though.
你应该上楼跟她打个招呼
You should go up there and say hey.
见一面 她很想你
Show your face. She misses you.
你也能有机会看看这地方变化有多大
And you get to see what they've done with the place.
毕竟你抛下我们跑去了圣文森医院
Since, you know, you done left us for Saint Vincent's.
现在是圣文森医院的人了
You're Saint Vincent's.
看看你 现在多厉害
Think you, think you fancy now.
-好吧 宝贝  -好了
- Okay, baby. - All right.
你今天好好工作
You have a good day at work.
我们今晚再见
And I'll see you later on tonight?
是的 今晚见 今晚见
Yes, you will. Yes, you will.
亲一个
Come here.
今晚见 宝贝
Later, man.
和纸杯蛋糕一样美味
Tasting like a cupcake.
我今晚会更加美味
I'm gonna be tasting like that tonight.
你在玩火
Don't start nothin'.
-谢谢  -你在玩火
- Thank you. - Don't start nothin'.
你还记得我当初说
Remember how I said
我做护士不是为了看着病人一个个去世的
I didn't become a nurse to help people die?
你看我现在
Well, look at me now.
每天上班都知道有新生命在等着你
I mean, it's so great to come to work
是一件多美好的事情
knowing that life awaits me.
还有婴儿的奶香
And the smell of babies?
这就是我的新天堂
It's my new happy place.
我都快认不出这里了
You know, I don't even recognize this place anymore.
换上了全新的设备
They got all of this brand-new equipment,
终于把这破墙重新粉刷了
and they finally painted these nasty-ass walls.
艾滋病患者数量减少后
The hospital magically came up with a budget
医院的各项开支预算
for all sorts of things once AIDS patients
都奇迹般地增加了
didn't come in as often.
天啊 新型药品简直就是奇迹
God, those new drugs are a fucking miracle.
我现在状态极佳
I've never felt better.
我真为你骄傲 你从未放弃
I'm so proud that you never gave up.
你现在身体健康
You're healthy.
有一个性感男友
You have a hot man.
还在圣文森医院找到了新工作
A new job at Saint Vincent's.
你肯定会快快乐乐 健康长寿 布兰卡
You're gonna live a very long and happy life, Blanca.
我之前一直都不信 朱迪
You know, I didn't believe that for the longest time, Judy.
但现在 我觉得你可能没错
But now, I think you might be right.
所以我成为了志愿者
That's why I volunteer.
我得把大家给予我的力量传递下去
I got to give back what was once freely given to me.
我仿佛能看见普雷·泰尔微笑地看着你
I see Pray Tell looking down at you, smiling.
我一直能听见他的声音
I hear him all the time.
真的
I do.
有时他给我提一些建议
Sometimes he gives me advice.
有时给我讲笑话
And sometimes he tells me a joke.
但他带给我最多的是安心
But most times he gives me reassurance
告诉我他会照看着我 一切都会好的
that I'm taken care of and that everything is gonna be okay.
继续听他的话吧
Keep listening to him.
我就是
I do.
看这些宝宝
Look at the babies.
-他们多可爱啊  -真漂亮啊
- Aren't they sweet? - They are beautiful.
35117号病人
Patient 35117?
萨法莉
Safaree,
你的艾滋检测是阳性
you tested positive for HIV.
给
Here.
你需要给谁打个电话吗
Is there anyone you can call?
朋友 家人
Friends? Family?
我六个月前才搬过来
I just moved here six months ago.
家人不肯跟我联系了
My parents don't speak to me no more.
我没人可以依靠
I ain't got no one.
你在码头那边拉客吗
Have you been working the pier?
我都清楚
I know it well.
-真的吗  -对的
- You do? - Yeah.
像你这么大的时候 我也在那里拉客
I used to work there myself when I was your age.
过去有六个码头
Back then, there were six piers.
现在只有一个了
And now there's only one.
听着
Look.
当我知道自己艾滋阳性的时候
When I found out that I was HIV positive,
还没有研发出有效药物
there weren't any drugs that were available.
艾滋病与死刑无异
AIDS was a death sentence.
但现在患者可以健康长寿
But now people are living long and healthy lives,
只要我们能坚持吃药
as long as we keep taking our meds
谨遵医嘱
and listening to what the doctors say.
-你也是阳性  -我是
- You're HIV positive? - I am.
你看看我现在 只要按要求服药
And I'm proof you are gonna be okay,
你也会没事的
if you follow the protocols.
我负担不起这些
I can't afford all that.
所以我会给你提供帮助
Well, see, that's why I'm here to help.
我会帮你报名
I am gonna help you get signed up
参加艾滋药物协助计划
for the AIDS Drug Assistance Program.
考虑到你的收入情况
Depending on your income,
你可能不需要为医疗服务花一分钱
you might not even have to pay a penny for your health care.
我跟你说
And let me tell you something.
你会没事的
You are gonna be okay.
要不这样
How about this?
周六晚上有一场大型活动
There is a function happening on Saturday night.
你可能会喜欢
Something I think you might enjoy.
我也是在那儿找到了自己的社群
It's where I found my community.
找到了希望
And where I found my hope.
看来不只有我们有这想法
Looks like we aren't the only ones who had the idea
闺蜜聚餐
for a ladies' lunch.
这叫"欲望都市"效应
Well, it is the Sex and the City effect.
所以女士们都进城来泄欲吗
These ladies all came into the city to have sex?
你没看过"欲望都市"吗
You ever seen Sex and the City?
你家没有家庭影院频道吗
Yeah, girl. You ain't got HBO?
对啊 你那么有钱
Yeah, you loaded.
我还以为你肯定会大肆挥霍
I figured you would have splurged
买那些会员电影资源呢
on the premium movie package by now.
-没错  -娱乐时间 家庭影院 电影频道
- Right. - Showtime, HBO, Cinemax.
同意
Word.
-富婆  -我的豪华公寓里可没有电视
- Rich girl. - I don't have television in my penthouse.
这东西只会腐蚀你的大脑 把它变成一堆糨糊
It rots your brain and turns it to Cream of Wheat.
老实说 我试着看过那部剧
Okay, look. I have to be honest, I tried watching that show.
首先 我没见过哪个女人会那么频繁地谈论性
And first of all, I ain't never seen women talk about sex as much as they do.
其次 这剧不如改名叫
And second of all, they need to call it.
"白人都市"
Being White and the City.
主角没有一个非裔
'Cause ain't none of them girls got a Black
-或者拉丁裔  -一个都没有
- or Latina friend. - Not one.
配角里也没有
Not even a sidekick.
让我猜猜看 大都会吗
Let me guess, Cosmopolitan?
多谢夸奖 都市丽人本人
Thank you. Yes, I am.
宝贝 那是鸡尾酒的名字
Bitch, a Cosmo is a drink
"欲望都市"里女主最爱的鸡尾酒
that the Sex and the City ladies love.
我要真正的酒
I'll have a real drink.
尊尼获加 纯饮加冰
Johnny Walker on the rocks.
最好是蓝牌
Blue Label if you have it.
[尊尼获加限量顶级醇酿]
四杯 谢谢
Bring four, actually.
我才不要让电视里的白人女孩
I refuse to let some TV show about white girls
定义我们的吃喝 我们的闺蜜聚会
define how we eat, drink and gather as girlfriends.
我们一直是自己的主宰
We've always made our own rules,
现在也是一样
and we ain't stopping now.
-没错  -同意
- I know that's right. - Heard that.
我跟那些黑手党说
I told those mafia gentlemen,
我了解男人
I know men.
我知道怎么让他们硬起来
I know what turns them on.
没错 色情电话行业利润丰厚
Yes, phone sex was lucrative,
但那是因为那时没有更好的选择
but only because there wasn't a better option.
而现在
Now there is.
有了网络视频平台
Webcam interactions.
就不需要再凭空想象
Remove the need for the imagination
还可以收两倍的钱
and you can charge twice the price.
光这一点就够我买下博卡拉顿的公寓了
That alone pays for my condo in Boca Raton.
孩子们 我之前只能算是有钱
Darlings, I was rich before,
现在 就算在大街上掉了一千美元
but now if I drop a thousand dollars on the street,
我都不想浪费时间给它捡起来
I don't even bother wasting time to pick it up.
话说得这么绝 伊莱察
Well, you talking real tough, Elektra.
我可是知道你悄悄地捐钱给医院
But I know you quietly giving money to those hospitals
资助戒毒所 来帮助那些女孩
and those drug-treatment facilities to help the girls.
她还为她们的激素治疗和变性手术买单
And she's paying for hormones and surgeries, too.
跨性别侠盗罗宾汉
A regular transsexual Robin Hood.
小点声 女士们
Shh! Don't be so loud, ladies.
我可是公认的冷酷无情 我得维持高冷的形象
I have a reputation as a cold, hard bitch to uphold.
收到 对了 如果你需要会计
Okay, well, if you ever decide you need a new accountant
管理你报给政府的资产
to deal with the money you actually declare to the government,
打给我就行 第一曼哈顿
give me a call, because First Manhattan
刚把我调去他们的税务部门
just moved me over to their tax department.
-什么  -我现在负责税务相关的业务
- What? - And I am helping people with their taxes now.
-天啊 露露 太棒了  -恭喜
- What? Lulu, that is incredible. - Congratulations.
-人上人了啊 是夸你呢  -对
- So bougie, in a good way. - Right.
你呢 安吉尔 你最近怎么样
Well, what about you, Angel? What's your update?
我儿子上三年级了
My baby started third grade.
真好
Okay.
做全职妈妈真的...
You know, being a full-time mother is...
是世界上最疯狂
It's just the most craziest,
最美好的事
most beautiful thing in the world.
我每天早上会给他做早餐
I make breakfast for him every morning.
虽然只是牛奶麦片 但...
It's just cereal and milk, but...
-拜托  -我会很正式地铺上餐巾什么的 好吗
- Girl. - I put a napkin out and everything. Okay?
-不到中午你能醒吗  -我每天都起早
- You wake up before noon? - Every day.
-好吧  -除了周日 妈妈可以睡懒觉
- Okay. - Except Sunday, that's Mommy's morning to sleep in.
真不错
I heard that.
还有 帕比带我重新回归业界了
And Papi's getting me back in the game, y'all.
他们让我去拍一款新发胶的广告
They putting me on a bottle of this new hairspray
专门给我们这种又厚又卷的头发用的
that's for real thick, curly hair, just like ours.
我给你们一人留了一瓶
I'm-a get y'all bottles.
我天 我忘记跟你们说戴蒙的事了
My God. I forgot to tell y'all about Damon.
-他给我写了一封信  -真的吗
- He sent me a letter, y'all. - Really?
对 他现在住芝加哥
Yeah, he's in Chicago,
和一个坐拥三家舞蹈工作室的好男人同居了
living with some nice man who's got three dance studios
他就是工作室的舞蹈老师
that he teaches in.
他让我代他向你们问好
And he wanted me to send y'all all his love.
真好 他也有干爹了
Well, that's lovely. He has a sugar daddy.
天啊
My God.
我们可都知道你的近况 布兰卡妈妈
And we all know about you, Mother Blanca.
现在是正式的护士了
A real, official nurse.
受过教育 顺利毕业 国家认证的护士
Educated, graduated and certified by the state.
谁能想到你真能找到一条路
Who would have guessed that you would have found a way
把你对同胞无穷无尽的善良变现呢
to monetize your annoyingly endless kindness for your fellow man.
我真为你骄傲
I am so proud of you.
我的甜心 我的布兰卡
My heart. My Blanca.
好了 行了
Okay, stop.
美满的结局只属于电影
Happy endings are for movies.
我们经历了太多痛苦 不会自欺欺人地
We done been through too much pain to fool ourselves
认为一切不幸都过去了
into thinking that all the bad is in the past,
但我还是相信... 有快乐的时刻
but I do believe in... happy moments.
有时只持续一分钟 有时持续一年
Sometimes they last a minute, sometimes a year.
但当快乐到来...
But when they come...
你要做的只是接受和庆祝 所以...
you just got to recognize and celebrate, so...
敬我们一起的快乐时光
Here's to all of our happy moments together.
我们不仅活了下来 我们还要活出彩
Not only did we survive, but we are thriving.
-干杯  -阿门 碰 碰 碰 碰
- Cheers. - Amen. Clink, clink, clink, clink, clink.
-干杯 妈妈  -干杯
- Cheers, Mama. - Yes.
靠 我得走了
Shit. Look, I got to go.
我得帮那些孩子准备今晚的走秀
I got to help these kids get ready for the ball tonight.
布兰卡母亲这么快就有别的孩子了
Ay, Mother Blanca and her children already?
这些孩子简直拿奖拿到手软
Okay, listen. These kids are trophy-winning machines.
你为什么坚持要回到那个又臭又闷的房间呢
Why do you insist on going back to that sweaty, airless room?
我们已经飞上枝头了
Can't you see we've all outgrown it?
伊莱察 人总是飞不出自己的家庭的
Elektra, you know you can't outgrow your family.
况且 你要记得舞会最初
Besides, you got to remember why the balls started
存在的意义
in the first place.
那是让我们发掘一切可能性的地方
They were a place for all of us to be all of them things
哪怕世界不允许我们的存在
that we weren't allowed to be out in the world.
我们有多少次商业女强人的主题走秀
All right, how many times have we walked Businesswoman?
现在你真的成了女强人 伊莱察
And now you a real one, Elektra.
还有传奇T台秀 安吉尔
Or Runway, Miss Angel.
现在你可以在真正的T台大放异彩
And now you actually walk the real runways.
我们走秀的时候不是在做样子
We weren't pretending when we walked those categories,
是在做准备
we were preparing.
久而久之 终会成功
Faking it until we made it.
最重要的是
And more than anything,
那是我们的宣言
we made a statement.
我们值得拥有梦想 实现梦想
That we deserve to dream and have our dreams fulfilled.
当我们站在舞池里
When we were walking those balls,
身边的人都在见证我们的无限可能
we beared witness to our possibilities.
我们对彼此说 姐妹 我看到你了
And we say to each other, "Yeah, girl, I see you.
我看到你未来的潜力了
I see who you are and who you can be."
外界的人们 要我们躲躲藏藏
And then the outside world, they tell us to hide.
但在舞厅...
But in the balls...
我们昂首阔步
they tell us to strut.
我们决不能放弃舞会
We can never give up on the balls.
布兰卡 你这番话太精彩了
Blanca, that is so beautiful,
但我今晚有点事 姐妹
but I can't make it tonight, girl.
我保证以后一定去
But I promise I'm-a come by soon.
现在是报税季
It's tax season, girl.
你也理解
You understand.
好吧 安吉尔呢
Okay. Angel?
不了 我们家宝贝鼻子不舒服
No, my baby, he got the sniffles.
我得回家照顾他
I got to go home and take care of my child.
妈...
Ma...
又臭 又闷...
Sweaty, airless...
不去
No.
好了 我知道你们都忙
Okay, look. I know y'all busy,
都有自己的生活
and y'all have your own lives,
我们还能再找机会聚聚吗
but can we do this again soon?
-当然  -肯定的
- Yes, of course. - Yes, of course.
-这还用说  -必须的
- Of course, come on. - Yes, of course.
我爱你们每一个人
I love each and every last one of you.
甚至包括你 伊莱察妈妈
Even you, Mother Elektra.
应该是尤其爱我
Especially me.
随你怎么说
Whatever.
-再见 爱你  -爱你哦
- Bye. I love you. - Love you, girl.
-再见  -再见 小圣母
- I'll see you. - See you, Mother Teresa.
抱歉 借过
Excuse me. Sorry.
你打扮得不错啊
Ooh, you look good, boo-boo.
这件衣服太棒了 宝贝
Ooh, definitely wear this, baby.
妈妈 抱歉
Hi, Mama. Oops, sorry.
迪昂 你迟到了
Dionne, you're late.
想做伊万吉丽斯塔家的人
Now, if you're gonna be an Evangelista,
就要遵守我的家规
you got to follow my rules.
凡事宜早
Early is on time.
准点即迟 我知道
And on time is late. I know.
对不起 爸爸
I'm sorry, Father.
口头上知道有什么用 我要看到行动
I don't need your words. I want action.
爸爸我从天命真女的排练现场提前离开
If Father can leave rehearsal with Destiny's Child early,
[著名女子组合 碧昂丝原团]
你还有什么借口
you have no excuses.
布兰卡祖母也迟到了啊
But Grandma Blanca was late, too.
不好意思 大小姐
Um, excuse me, Miss Thing.
我上出租车的时候衣服都穿得好好的了
I had all my finery intact when I got into my cab ride.
真是谢谢你啊
Thank you very much.
还有 谁允许你们这么质问自己的祖母的
And when was it okay for y'all to call y'all grandmother out?
那句话怎么说的
You know what they say.
一报还一报
Snitches get stitches!
好了 你要说说这帮孩子了
Okay. You need to talk to these children.
看看这个 看
Look at this. Look.
伊万吉丽斯塔
你们都是伊万吉丽斯塔家的人
You all are Evangelistas.
伊万吉丽斯塔
这个家族不仅是舞厅王者
Now, this house is known for more than just slaying a category.
我们... 所有人... 都是一家人
We... all of us... are a family.
我们的第一条家规是什么
Now, what's my number-one rule?
伊万吉丽斯塔家人永远
Evangelistas always show up.
无条件地
For each other.
-支持彼此  -没错
- No questions asked. - That's right.
第二条家规...
Rule number two...
展现自我
Show up for yourself.
好了 过来吧
All right, y'all. Come here.
我有话要说
I got something to say.
你们来到这座城市都是为了寻找自我
Each of you came into the city to find yourselves,
看吧 你们找到了彼此
and look at you, you found each other.
你们都是这传承的一部分
You're part of a legacy.
我们的家庭是基于爱 忠诚 和支持
A chosen family rooted in love, loyalty and support.
-没错  -是不是
- That's right. - Right?
永远要记住 如果你感到迷茫
Don't ever forget, if you get lost,
爱会指引你回到家族
love will lead you back to your house.
现在去舞厅尽情展现吧
Now get out there and show ballroom
我们的光芒来自
the glory of being a what?
伊万吉丽斯塔
Evangelista!
-好了  -还有...
- All right. - And please...
希望外面的观众里有我未来的男人
let my future man be out there watching.
老天保佑 阿门
In Jesus' name. Amen!
-阿门  -哈利路亚
- Amen. - Hallelujah.
准备好了吗
Are y'all ready?
准备好了
Yeah!
现在 欢迎全新的伊万吉丽斯塔之家
For the new, reimagined, House of Evangelista!
首先是第一个主题 面容主题
We gonna start off with the first category, Face.
有请迪昂·伊万吉丽斯塔
We got Dionne Evangelista here.
看到你了
We see you. Yeah!
看她的颧骨 她的下巴
She's giving cheekbones. She's giving chin.
好了 好了 下一位
All right, all right. Up next,
逼真皇后
we got Femme Queen Realness.
就在那儿 货真价实
That's it right there. It's real,
女性之美 皇后气势
it's femme and it's queen-like.
贾斯提斯登场了
We got Justice.
[Justice本意为"正义"]
贾斯提斯
Justice, no peace.
[No Justice. No Peace. "无正义 无和平"是黑人运动经典标语]
真是怪异
This is bizarre!
我完全无法理解
I don't know what the fuck it is,
但是我喜欢
but I like it. Shit!
折舞主题
We got Vogue.
缇娜 太美了
We got Teena. Gorgeous!
让我们见识见识 缇娜·玛丽
Yes. Give it to us, Teena Marie!
秀起来 秀起来 秀起来
Give it to us. Give it to us. Get it. Get it!
来了 来了 来了
Get it! Get it! Get it!
就是这样
That's it right there.
来吧 来吧 来吧
Get it! Get it! Get it! Get it!
浪起来
Go, go!
就是这么拽 来吧
That's a bad bitch right there. Get it!!
就是这样
Yes, bitch!
从上面看你就像莉儿·金一样
Up in here looking like Lil' Kim!
[著名嘻哈歌手]
真有范儿 怎么
You got it going on. What-what?!
好了好了 我们来看看
All right, all right, all right. Let's get these bitches
分数如何 看看 十分
their scores? What do we got? We got a ten,
十分 十分 十分 十分
ten, ten, ten, ten.
十分大满贯
Tens across the board!
伊万吉丽斯塔之家
The House of Evangelista.
掌声送给她们
Give it to 'em, y'all.
好了 把奖杯给他们吧
One love! Give these babies their trophy.
真棒
Ain't they cute?
好了 好了 好了
All right, all right, all right, all right.
安静一下 安静 都坐下
Settle on down. Settle on down. Sit your ass down.
今晚还有一个特殊环节
We got a special moment of the night about to happen.
一位特别的嘉宾
We have a very special guest
即将为我们颁出重磅大奖
to present a very important award.
让我们请出传奇人物
I would like to introduce the legend,
独一无二...
the one, the only...
和她一比 就连戴安娜·罗斯
The only bitch who makes Diana Ross
也成了廉价百货店的平凡路人
look like her ass shops at Ross.
伊莱察·阿班邓斯·伊万吉丽斯塔
Ha-ha! Elektra Abundance Evangelista.
谢谢你们的热烈欢迎
Thank you for that very warm greeting.
舞厅代表着家
Ballroom is home.
舞厅代表着家人
Ballroom is family.
舞厅代表着爱
Ballroom is love.
如果没有这个社群
And if it weren't for this community,
我成为不了今天的我
I wouldn't be where I am today.
我不会有现在的成就
I wouldn't be who I am,
要不是因为许多女性 我的姐妹们
if it weren't for the many women, my sisters,
她们在我孤立无助时伸出援手
who lifted me up when I couldn't do it myself.
正如泰隆所说
As Tyrone observed, correctly,
是的 我是偶像
yes, I am an icon.
但并非一夜之功
But that didn't happen overnight.
我不懈努力才留下这永不磨灭的宣言
I worked hard to leave an indelible statement.
我知道要成为传奇背后所需的努力和牺牲
I know the work and sacrifice it takes to become a legend.
成为传奇并不只是
To be a legend isn't simply
比赛和赢下奖杯那么简单
about competing and collecting trophies.
而关乎你是否能代表我们的社群
It's about how you represent this community.
我曾目睹过这位女性孜孜不倦地工作
And I have seen this woman work tirelessly,
不止是为了家人 还是为了我们所有人
not only for family, but for all of us.
能称她为我的女儿 我感到十分骄傲
I am proud to call her my daughter
最后...
and finally...
我将传奇人物奖授予
bestow legendary status
独一无二的...
on the one and only...
我亲爱的女儿...
my baby girl...
布兰卡·伊万吉丽斯塔
Blanca Evangelista!
伊万吉 丽斯塔
Evange-lista!
-什么  -伊万吉 丽斯塔
- What?! - Evange-lista!
伊万吉 丽斯塔
Evange-lista!
好了好了
All right, all right, all right.
非常好 感谢伊万吉丽斯塔家族
That's cute. We thank you so much, Evangelista.
现在我们稍作休息
So, now we gonna take a little break
然后继续回到比赛
and then we gonna get right back to this shit, all right?
我没有什么特别的服装能穿
I didn't have anything special to wear.
别担心 有我们呢
Don't worry. We got you.
你们听好了
Hey, y'all. Listen up.
她是你们的新姐妹 萨法莉
This y'all new sister, Safaree.
好了 我们得尽快带她去后台准备
All right, and look, we got to help her get backstage quickly.
贾斯提斯 帮她化个妆
So, Justice, dust this mug.
缇娜 从衣架上拿件超好看的衣服来
And, Teena, pull something sickening from that rack.
等等 什么情况
Wait, wait. Wait, what's going on?
不好意思 亲爱的 等会就是你的舞厅出道秀了
I'm sorry, honey. You walking your first ball.
欢迎加入伊万吉丽斯塔之家
Welcome to The House of Evangelista.
-来吧 带她过去 走吧  -准备好了吗
- Come on, take her. Let's go. - You ready?
好
Okay.
妈妈
Mama.
姐妹 你还在这干嘛呢
Girl, what are you still doing here?
我还以为你今晚就坐这不走了呢
I thought you were staying all night.
不是 我...
No, I...
我只是...
I was just...
晚安
Good night.
今天的主题是爱
The category is Love, y'all!
今晚的评委肯定都磕嗨了
The judges was definitely on some bullshit tonight.
我们不可能一个主题都赢不了
There's no way we should have lost every category.
布兰卡
Hey, Blanca.
我有个问题要问传奇人物
I got a question for the legend.
这是我们空手而归的第三次舞会
This is the third ball we leaving empty-handed.
要怎么做才能赢奖
What we got to do to snag us some trophies?
哎哟哟
Well, well, well.
看看这伤心的皇后
Look at the sad queens.
对评分不满吗
Disappointed about our scores, are we?
这不是你们第一次失利
This ain't gonna be the first time you lose,
肯定也不会是最后一次
and it sure won't be the last.
成功并没有什么秘密或是捷径
Ain't no secrets or shortcuts to success.
只需要... 一直努力
You just... you keep trying.
要是想放弃了呢
What if you want to give up, though?
觉得没有继续努力的理由了呢
And you feel ain't no reason to keep going?
你觉得要是放弃了 我还能有今天吗
You think this would've ever happened if I gave up?
你是一家之母吗
You the house mother?
回头看看
Look around.
你想要继续努力的理由
You want a reason to continue?
不就站在你面前吗
It's standing right there in front of you.
这就是了
There it is, right there.
家族是这些年轻的孩子们
Houses are homes to all the little boys and girls
未曾有过的庇护所
who never had one.
他们会一直涌向这里
And they gonna keep coming here,
涌向纽约 就像太阳照常升起
to New York City. Sure as the sun rises.
你要做的就是...
So, what you got to do is...
更加努力
Work harder.
看向更高的地方
Reach higher.
心怀梦想 直到...
And dream big until you...
取得成功
Triumph.
直到你取得成功
Until you triumph.
今天不成 总有一天会成
It won't happen today, but one day.
当你成功时
And when you do,
我还会在那里面...
I'm-a be right in there...
为你加油
cheering you on.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠